(ゼツ)忍の物語は
母が復活するための物語だ。
The tale of shinobi…
is the tale of restoring Mother.
お前たちに見せてやる。
I shall now show you two…
飴玉はないが紙芝居の始まりだ。
I don't have any candy,
but the puppet show
is about to begin…
Kaguya Otsutsuki
あれを見ろ。
光ってる。 怪しいぞ。
Look at that!
It's glowing!
It looks suspicious!
(テンジ)何だあれは？
What is it?
星か？
あんな星があるものか！
Is it a star?
That's no star, it's moving!
動いている。
How terrifying!
追え。
はっ！
Follow it!
Yes, sir!
女…。 この者が
天からやってきたと申すのか？
A woman?
And you're saying that
she came from the heavens?
はい。 光の落ちた場所から
この女が出てきました。
Yes…
This woman appeared in the spot
where the light had fallen.
((用心しろ))
Be careful!
フム… 名を何と申す？
Hmm…
What is your name?
答えぬか！
このお方は祖の国の皇→
Answer him!
The man standing before you is
the King of the Land of Sou,
テンジ様におわせられるぞ！
Lord Tenji!
これ！
恐らくこの女は→
You there!
The Land of Ka must have
sent this woman to spy on us!
彼の国の回し者に違いありません。
締め上げて素性を吐かせよ。
はっ。
Interrogate her and
make her confess!
- Yes, sir!
待て。
Wait.
うっ…。
あっ…。
こやつ！
何をした？
You—!
What did you do?!
うっ…。
どうした？
What's the matter?
(カグヤ)わらわの名は カグヤ。
My name is Kaguya.
カグ… ヤ？
Kagu…ya?
神樹を見守る者。
I am the one who protects
the Divine Tree.
(アイノ)このたび
カグヤ様のお世話をするよう→
I have been assigned to
take care of your needs.
おおせつかりました
アイノと申します。
I am Aino…
カグヤ様？
Lady Kaguya?
あの樹は 数千年前に忽然と生えて
見る間に大木になったとか。
Several millennia ago,
that tree appeared out of nowhere
and grew into a massive tree
before our very eyes.
(アイノ)でも 恐ろしい噂も聞きます。
But I have heard
frightening rumors too.
あの樹に近づくと→
Anyone who approaches it is quickly
consumed by a demon spirit
たちまちのうちに精根が尽き果て
枯れ木のように死んでしまうとか。
and dies like a withered branch.
あっ！ すみません
よけいなことを言って。
Forgive me for speaking
of such things!
気にすることはない。
Do not worry.
For it is true…
本当のことです。
(アイノ)えっ？
Huh?
それも いつか…。
And some day…
テンジ様！ 彼の国の スザク大臣と
ゲンブ大臣がお見えになりました。
Lord Tenji!
Ministers Suzaku and Genbu from
the Land of Ka are here to see you.
(スザク)これは
彼の国と祖の国の国境である。
This is the border between
the Land of Ka and the Land of Sou.
問題は この湖。
The issue is this lake.
この地は 現在
祖の国の領地になっておるが→
Presently, this region is said to be
part of the Land of Sou…
こたび 彼の国で発見された
古文書によれば→
But an ancient manuscript
was recently discovered.
On it, has been recorded
from time immemorial,
古来 彼の国の領地と
記されておる。
that this land was originally within
the Land of Ka's territory.
(スザク)この地を
我らに返していただきたい。
We wish to have this land
returned to us.
しかし その湖は
祖の国の農地の水源。
But that lake is our source of water
for our farmlands in the Land of Sou.
それを貴殿の国へ渡したら…。
If I were to return that land…
(ゲンブ)どのような事情があろうが→
No matter what situation arises,
to return what was stolen
to its true owner…
盗んだものは
持ち主に返すべきと存ずる。
それが物事の道理。
is the right thing to do.
よき返事が聞けぬ場合は 祖の国に
どのような災いが降りかかるか…。
If we do not receive
a favorable answer,
we cannot be responsible
for whatever misfortune
責任は負えませぬぞ。
befalls the Land of Sou!
(スザク)まぁ まぁ！
Now, now…
そちらにも いろいろと 事情を
整理する時間が必要でござろう。
I'm sure you will need some time
to prepare and take care of things.
後日 改めて 答えを
伺いにまいることとしましょう。
We shall return in a few days
to hear your answer.
そういえば テンジ殿は
天女を妾にしたとか。
By the way,
I understand you have taken
a celestial maiden as a concubine.
(ゲンブ)なんとも言えぬ
神秘的な美しさを持つ美女と→
I hear she is indescribably
beautiful and mysterious.
お聞きしたが…。
私も見てみたいものだ！
I am most curious to see her.
(ゲンブ/スザク)アハハハハハ！
発見された古文書など
おそらく 彼の国のでっちあげ…。
Without a doubt,
this recently discovered artifact
is a fabrication by the Land of Ka.
わかっている。
I am aware of that…
彼の国は 隣国に因縁をつけては
戦を仕掛け 領土を広げてきた。
The Land of Ka makes false claims
against neighboring lands
as a pretext to war.
That's how they've
expanded their lands.
今回も同じだ。
This case is no different.
だが 彼の国の戦力は
我が祖の国の３倍…。
But they have an army three times
greater than the Land of Sou.
戦となれば 勝ち目はない。
There is no way we can win.
スザクとゲンブ… 彼らを使者として
よこしたところを見ると→
Suzaku and Genbu…
Sending those two
as messengers means…
彼の国は本気。 このまま
おめおめと引き下がるとは…。
The Land of Ka is serious.
We cannot be meek—
テンジ様！ 受けて立ちましょうぞ!!
Lord Tenji, let's stand up to them!
どうせ滅ぶなら
祖の国の意地を見せつけてやる！
If we are doomed anyway,
let's go down fighting and
show them the pride of the Sou!
そう慌てるな。
Do not panic just yet.
テンジ様。
Lord Tenji!
カグヤは何をしておる？
What is Kaguya doing?
カグヤ様は 毎日 ああやって
空を見上げておいでです。
Lady Kaguya spends her days
looking up at the sky like that.
まるで どなたかが ご自分を
お迎えにいらっしゃるかのように。
It's as though she's waiting for
someone to come for her…
(アイノ)村人たちの噂では
カグヤ様は 空からやってきたと…。
According to the villagers,
they say Lady Kaguya
came from the heavens…
それが… カグヤとの出会いは
覚えていないのだ。
The thing is…I don't remember
my first encounter with Kaguya.
は…？
Oh?
それを借りられぬか？
えっ？ これですか？
May I borrow that?
Huh?
Oh this?
ずっと 夜風に吹かれていたのでは
寒かろう。
You must be freezing, standing in
the cold night air for so long.
あの輝く光の世界は
常に美しく穏やかなのだろうか？
I wonder if that glowing world above
is always beautiful and at peace…
(テンジ)こうして 夜空を見上げると
何か 不思議な気がする。
A strange feeling comes over me
as I gaze up at the night sky…
真っ黒な空間に あのような
美しい光が浮かんでいるなんて…。
The fact that such a beautiful light
lies afloat in pitch darkness…
あれは いったい
なんなのだろう？
Just what is it?
Will I ever be able to go there?
私も いつか そこに行くことが
できるのだろうか とね…。
そなたは 毎日
空を見つめているそうな。
I hear that you gaze up
at the sky every night…
誰かを待っているのか？
Are you waiting for someone?
たとえ そうであってもいい。
It's all right if that's the case.
お前が寂しくなって
空を見上げるときには→
From now on, whenever you're
lonely and look up at the sky,
私は いつも
隣にいることにしよう。
I shall be by your side.
そなたは何か望むものはないか？
Is there anything that you desire?
わらわが望むのは争いのない平和。
What I wish…is for peace
with no more fighting.
平和か…。
Peace…huh?
あれは 彼の国の…
あんにゃろ ナメやがって！
They're from the Land of Ka!
Why that—!
They're messing with us!
やめるんだ！ あいつらが
挑発してるのがわからねえのか。
Don't!
Can't you see they're just
trying to provoke us?!
クソッ。
Damn it!
テンジ様！
Lord Tenji!
国境では
彼の国の者たちによる悪さが→
The mischief caused by
the Land of Ka at our border
ますます激しくなっております。
is growing steadily worse!
何か手を打たなければ…
すでに民の怒りは限界かと。
Unless we take action…
the farmers' ire will
reach a breaking point!
わかっている。 だが決して→
I understand…
But I forbid you to confront
the Land of Ka.
彼の国の者に手を出してはならぬ。
しかし。
私が求めるのは平和だ。
But—!
I seek peace.
戦になれば 多くの者たちが死ぬ。
If fighting ensues, many will die.
彼の国とは和平交渉を進めるのだ。
We must move forward with peaceful
negotiations with the Land of Ka.
彼の国の者に手を出した者は
我が名のもとに死罪とする！
Anyone who makes a move
on the Land of Ka
will be executed on my order.
なんと…。
What is he thinking?
ハァ ハァ… テンジ様はおられるか？
Is Lord Tenji here?
Yes…
He comes nearly every night.
はい 毎日のように
お見えになります。
最近では カグヤ様も
心をお許しになったのか→
It seems Lady Kaguya has come to
accept his presence recently,
and they've been spending more
and more time together.
お二人でおられる時間も
ずいぶんと多くなって…。
I didn't ask you for details!
そんなことは聞いとらん！
テンジ様 テンジ様！
Lord Tenji! Lord Tenji!
何事だ？ こんな夜中に。
What do you want at this hour?
The Land of Ka is at the border
with a large army!
国境に彼の国の大軍勢が。
What?!
なに!?
Kaguya…
カグヤ 私はすぐに
出陣しなければならない。
I must depart for
the front immediately.
戦が？
To war?
No, this is for peace.
いや あくまで和平のために。
しかし 悪くすると…。
But if things should go wrong…
急いで身を隠す準備を。
はい。
Prepare to go into hiding right away!
Yes!
Do not worry.
I shall return right away.
心配するな
すぐに戻ってこられる。
Let's go!
我々も行くぞ。
はっ。
Yes!
Guard the castle.
館の守りは頼んだぞ。
Leave it to us.
お任せください。
ふむ カグヤとやらは
祖の国の都を離れたか。
So that Kaguya has left
the capital of Sou…
This is the perfect opportunity
to capture that woman.
これは この女を手に入れる
好機だな。
There's no need to rush.
そう慌てることもなかろう。
The Land of Sou
will be ours in no time.
もうすぐ 祖の国は
我らが手中に収まる。
It's just one woman…
Be patient.
女一人 そのときで
よいではないか。
It's my policy to get what I want
as fast as I can.
欲しいものは一刻も早く
いただくのが私の流儀だ。
好き者め。
You're hopeless…
Gather skilled men.
We're going after Kaguya.
手だれの者を集めよ
すぐにカグヤのあとを追う。
Yes, sir!
はっ。
You can't sleep?
(アイノ)眠れないのですか？
I'll stay with you.
私も お供します。
うっ！
Enemy attack!
Alert!
敵襲だ～ 出合え！
≪キャー！
Lady Kaguya! Lady Aino!
カグヤ様 アイノ様！
何事です？
What's going on?
So this is where you were hiding!
(スザク)
こんなところに隠れていたか。
何者です このお方を
テンジ様のご側室と知っての無礼か？
Who are you?!
You dare approach knowing that
this lady is Lord Tenji's concubine?!
Tenji?
テンジだと？
彼の国の私には関係ないな。
I'm from the Land of Ka,
why should I care about him?
The Land of Sou will fall very soon.
もう間もなく この国は滅びる。
つまり テンジのものは
私のものということさ。
To put it bluntly, what belongs to
Tenji will soon belong to me.
《スザク : 噂どおりの美貌だな。
それに気品がある》
The rumors were right…
such a beauty.
And very refined.
今からは私のものだ！
From this moment on, you are mine!
Lady Kaguya, please run!
カグヤ様 逃げて カグヤ様！
Lady Kaguya…
逃げられるか！
Like you can escape!
カグヤ様！
Lady Kaguya!
ほう この状況でも臆さぬか。
Even in this situation,
you're not scared…
ますます私の好みよのう。
Well, that just makes me
like you more!
捕らえよ！
Take her!
(２人)うわ～！
Do not touch me.
わらわに触れるな。
ちっ！
Don't back off!
ひるむな！
ああ～！
妖艶な正体は化け物であったか。
So the bewitching beauty
is actually a monster…
こ これで祖の国は
本当に終わりだな。
Th-The Land of Sou
is really doomed now…
早く軍勢を
引き上げていただきたい。
I would like you to withdraw
your troops immediately.
You seem to be under
the wrong impression, Lord Tenji.
テンジ殿は何か
勘違いしておるようだな。
We are not at war.
これは戦のためではなく
国境を守るための軍勢だ。
This army is just to
protect our boundary.
国境の守りに
このような大軍勢は…。
Such a large army just to
protect the boundary is…
I do not intend to wage war either.
わが国にも
戦の腹積もりはない。
それを証拠に 我が国では
彼の国の者に手を出した者は→
There's proof in the fact that
I have ordered anyone who draws
his sword against the Land of Ka
即刻死罪という命を
出してある。
to be executed immediately.
Oh, is that so?
ほう なるほど ならば
カグヤを死罪にしてもらいたい。
Then I want you to execute Kaguya.
This woman known as Kaguya killed
my vassal, and then tried to kill me!
カグヤと申す者 我が部下を殺し
私も殺そうとしたのだ。
そんな カグヤが？
Impossible…
Kaguya would never—!
ウソだと言うなら
この女に聞いてみるがよい。
If you think I'm lying,
ask this woman.
本当なのか？
Is it true?
はい カグヤ様は恐ろしい力で
彼の国の兵たちを。
Yes.
Lady Kaguya…
dispatched the soldiers of Ka
with frightening power…
テンジ殿 カグヤの首なくして
戦は止められませんぞ。
Lord Tenji!
Unless you behead Kaguya,
this war will not end!
戻るぞ。
I'm leaving.
その姿 大丈夫か？
What happened to you?
カグヤという女
とんだ もののけよ。
That woman Kaguya…
is a horrible monster.
化け物退治は ヤツらに任せ
その隙に全てをいただこうぞ。
Leave the witch-hunt to them…
And in the interim,
we'll conquer everything.
これをカグヤが？
子細はどうあれ→
Kaguya did this?
Whatever the reason,
スザク殿を手にかけようとしたことは
確かなようですな。
there seems to be no doubt that
she tried to kill Sir Suzaku.
カグヤ…。
Kaguya…
いかがいたしましょう テンジ様。
What are you going to do,
Lord Tenji?!
本当に カグヤ様の首を？
Are you really going to
execute Lady Kaguya?
差し出さなければ→
Unless I give them her head,
war will not be averted…
戦は回避できまい。
本当に それでよいのですな？
Are you really willing to do that?
全軍 カグヤを追うのだ。
Send all troops after Kaguya…
草の根を分けてでも捜し出せ。
Leave no stone unturned. Find her.
致し方あるまい。
I have no other choice…
あれは 追っ手？
これは祖の国の…。
それでは 追っ手はテンジ様。
急ぐのです。
わらわの運命は神樹とともに。
カグヤ様 テンジ様に事情を話せば
きっと お許しを…。
くっ…。
カグヤ様。
力が…。
カグヤ様
もしや お腹に ややこが…。
ひどい！ なのにテンジ様は…。
なんとしても神樹に。
行ってください ここは私が。
待って。
テンジ様！ 兵を お引きください。
カグヤ様のお腹には…。
アイノ！
テンジ様の…。
カグヤ様。
元気な… ややこ…。
アイノ！
今こそ 祖の国を滅ぼす機会だ。
押せ～！
これで祖の国は我らのもの。
カグヤ。
この世を照らせ 無限月読。
なんだ？
ぐあ～っ！
カグヤ。
お前は いったい何者なのだ…。
この地は わらわが治める。
わらわの子たちとともに。